<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Venkat Krishna</title>
        <link>https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Venkat Krishna</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 20:21:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Boomiyum Naanum - I and the Earth</title>
            <link>https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/i_and_my_life/boomiyum_naanum/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 20:21:00 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/i_and_my_life/boomiyum_naanum/</guid>
            <description>It was 7.30 in the morning and I was still rolling on my bed trying to read my e-mails with one eye &amp;lsquo;cause my other eye was too lazy to open itself. My Alexa started her routine by telling a fact of the day and she wished me &amp;ldquo;Happy Earth day, dude!&amp;rdquo; My other eye opened now. It&amp;rsquo;s Earth day! We all love our earth, don&amp;rsquo;t we? We do. It&amp;rsquo;s just that we forgot long back or we don&amp;rsquo;t know how to show that love.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was 7.30 in the morning and I was still rolling on my bed trying to read my e-mails with one eye &lsquo;cause my other eye was too lazy to open itself. My Alexa started her routine by telling a fact of the day and she wished me &ldquo;Happy Earth day, dude!&rdquo; My other eye opened now. It&rsquo;s Earth day! We all love our earth, don&rsquo;t we? We do. It&rsquo;s just that we forgot long back or we don&rsquo;t know how to show that love. So at 7.35, I decided that I&rsquo;ll write something to show my love towards our mother earth today.</p>
<p><img src="https://images.tribuneindia.com/cms/gall_content/2016/10/2016_10$largeimg12_Wednesday_2016_174930184.jpg" alt="Just a blue old earth"></p>
<p>Let me begin with some history of how earth day was created. It all started when two men in America concerned about the environment decided to conduct a teach-in at some college campus, hired one more person to organize the teach-ups, who built a team of 85 members all over the country and on April 22nd, 1970 on the first Earth Day, there were 20 million people on the roads of America. That was the largest single-day protest by humans in history. I will not bore y&rsquo;all with more history now. If you&rsquo;re interested to know more details, you know where to find it. <em>winks weirdly</em> You can also be a part of the community by just enrolling yourself on earthday.org</p>
<p>Now we all know why earth day is celebrated. To protect our planet from environmental crises such as climate change, water scarcity, ozone depletion, deforestation, and these are only a few of the actual problems we face right now. I can write the statistics about how these issues are real and an immediate threat to our lives but you can read all about that on the internet. The whole point of writing this was not to bombard you all with history and facts. I wanted to write about how serious it is for us to take care of our earth and how can we give back our love to it. I&rsquo;ve seen a kind of mentality in many people where they say, &ldquo;How can I stop global warming&rdquo;, &ldquo;How can I save the ocean&rdquo; and I think that&rsquo;s so stupid and mediocre. If you were also thinking the same, I&rsquo;m sorry but you&rsquo;re wrong. I mean if YOU can&rsquo;t then who can? It all starts with you. It really saddens me when someone tells me what can they do.</p>
<p>First of all, see for yourself if you&rsquo;re harming the environment in any way. Be aware all the time of how you&rsquo;re interacting with your environment. Fix that leaking tap. Close the tap while brushing your teeth. I&rsquo;ve seen people who just keep the water flowing while they&rsquo;re brushing because they&rsquo;re used to it! <em>rolls my eyes</em> While washing your face open the tap only a little so that it just fills your hand and close the tap while you&rsquo;re lathering up your face or hand. Also while washing your dishes there&rsquo;s no need to turn your tap all the way up. Do you know how many litres on average a person is wasting the water every day by just washing the face and hands? About 50 litres! People living in Bengaluru will know how costly it is to buy water for their homes. If we keep wasting our water like this then one day water would be the most valuable commodity in our world. Also, you guys know that Bengaluru has almost run out of groundwater right?</p>
<p>Use public transport whenever possible, and by whenever possible I mean mostly.  Bengalureans, please stop buying those cars dude. Buy an electric car if you really need one! Switch off your lights, fans and other electrical devices when not in use. Hibernate your PC don&rsquo;t put it in sleep mode! Stop using straws. Reduce your consumption of fish. Did you know it&rsquo;s not plastic but fishing actually kills the ocean? Oh and for god&rsquo;s sake man please separate your garbage! The bio-degradable and the non-bio-degradable are NOT the same. The non-bio-degradable ones can be recycled and by mixing them you&rsquo;re not only choking the recycling but you&rsquo;re also paving the way to pollute our environment. Both degradable and non-degradable would mix and react to create toxic elements which pollute our land, air and earth!</p>
<p>Okay, you all might think now that I&rsquo;m writing these things but do I follow them? Yes, I do. I&rsquo;ve been doing this for many years now. I don&rsquo;t remember when it all started but I&rsquo;ve always had this love for nature and our planet. Maybe because I grew up in a place rich with nature! I always open my tap less than halfway. I wait for a couple of seconds to fill my hands with water because I know saving those extra 10-15 seconds by opening the tap fully I&rsquo;m not going to invent the time machine. I don&rsquo;t have a bike or a car. I live near my office and I walk to my office. I prefer trains over buses to travel long distance. I switch my lights off and I tell everyone to do the same. I don&rsquo;t use plastic straws, plastic bottles. I&rsquo;m not saying I&rsquo;m a total environmental enthusiast. Like a full-blown gnani(sage) or something. I just do my best to save my earth.</p>
<p>Before I end this I&rsquo;ll tell you about this incident which happened today. I was having lunch with my parents and I was asking my parents how and where they used to buy vegetables, how my grandparents, great-grandparents and great-great-grandparents bought vegetables and other groceries and all. It was a very interesting conversation(you should ask your parents) and today I came to know that my parents had eaten two pulses which are extinct now. Yes, you read that right. They are dead. There are no more seeds to cultivate them. I was actually sad when I heard my parents saying that. Like the same, we don&rsquo;t see sparrows anymore in our homes. So many birds we don&rsquo;t see them. Peacocks used to come and play in our backyard and after 15 years I saw them once this year. That&rsquo;s how much we are killing our planet earth.
When you start doing it, people will ask you why?! Tell them, explain to them why you love your earth and why they should also and if they don&rsquo;t listen it&rsquo;s fine you keep doing it someday they&rsquo;ll listen. That&rsquo;s what I do.</p>
<p>Happy Earth Day! Peace.✌☮</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Udalum Naanum - I and my body</title>
            <link>https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/i_and_my_life/udalum_naanum/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 17:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/i_and_my_life/udalum_naanum/</guid>
            <description>Weird title, eh? It should be because our body is weird, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Actually, it is not. I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you something interesting(I hope :p) about our human body in this blog. Our body is evolving since I don&amp;rsquo;t know maybe half a million years ago or even more than that. They say our body is a temple. Temple is where we worship and keep it clean all the time.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Weird title, eh? It should be because our body is weird, isn&rsquo;t it? Actually, it is not. I&rsquo;m going to tell you something interesting(I hope :p) about our human body in this blog. Our body is evolving since I don&rsquo;t know maybe half a million years ago or even more than that. They say our body is a temple. Temple is where we worship and keep it clean all the time. Are we doing that with our bodies? Probably no.</p>
<p>With our bodies, our eating habits are also evolving. Are we conscious about that? What we eat makes a lot of difference in our day to day life. You must&rsquo;ve heard someone saying eating fruits in the morning gives them an extra boost throughout the day. Have you asked why? It&rsquo;s not just the fiber or the nutrition you get from them but how this nutrition reacts with your body is what actually matters. Let&rsquo;s take electrolyte. Electrolytes are substances that dissolve in a solvent and acquire electrical conductivity. Some of the electrolytes that we have in our body are sodium, potassium, chloride, etc., and some of the electrolyte-rich foods are banana, watermelon, coconut water, etc., Now what do they do in our body? They are responsible for controlling our involuntary muscles! Regulates the fluids in our bodies. Most of us must have felt this involuntary twitching in our muscles sometimes. It&rsquo;s nothing but an imbalance in our electrolyte level. So when you eat electrolyte-rich food in the morning your blood flow will be smooth and your heart will pump at ease!</p>
<p>Most of us must&rsquo;ve followed at least one of the myriad diets and checked how many calories we eat every day. How many of us actually know what&rsquo;s a calorie dude? A Calorie is a unit of energy and it denotes how much heat energy is required to increase the temperature of one gram of water by one degree celsius. We need energy for our body to function normally and live healthily. Our body basically burns the food we eat, produces, and uses the necessary energy by a process called metabolism. Now when there is more energy in our body to burn but you are not burning it you&rsquo;ll get fat. Also, when you eat empty calorie food(like junks, sodas which have no nutrition) you&rsquo;ll become unhealthy. So stop just looking at the calories and start looking into the details. Have a diversified diet that contains all the nutrients. Take a pen and paper write down what all the foods you like or you know is healthy and you want to eat it. Then open your browser and start researching what the food actually contains, you&rsquo;ll be surprised! You may ask if I did all these? Yes I did and I lost 15 kilos in 3 months but after a year I&rsquo;m back to my o(the panda from The KungFu Panda) form. The whole motive of writing this blog is to motivate me to go back to my Mantis form.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll tell you what I did. The first thing is to find the TDEE for your body. TDEE is an acronym for Total Daily Energy Expenditure. It gives you how many calories you need per day approximately. There are plenty of calculators to calculate your TDEE on the internet. After that, use any mobile application to keep a track of your calorie intake every day. I used HealthifyMe and I used to just record whatever I eat, drink. Everything. It took me a couple of weeks to understand how my eating habits were and after around two and a half weeks I started controlling my diet. In fact, after around 10 days I almost knew how many calories my food has kind of a muscle memory. I never ate anything after 7PM, mostly it was 6PM. I did intermittent fasting twice to thrice in a week. One thing I did not do was any physical exercise, and man I regret that. After seeing the results, I was very happy and I just totally ignored the workout part. That made me very unhealthy later. So the advice is to work out a little according to your body and how you want your muscles. Consistent is the key, say no to that one chocolate, say no to that one dinner outside. Whenever you feel like having a cheat meal or a cheat day ask yourself why you started this? That&rsquo;ll keep you going.</p>
<p>Being said that, take care of your body, your mind will be taken care of.</p>
<p>Happy dieting!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Kadavulum Naanum - I and the God</title>
            <link>https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/i_and_my_life/kadavulum_naanum/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 17:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://muttalkadavul.github.io/posts/i_and_my_life/kadavulum_naanum/</guid>
            <description>Who created us? When I ask this question the very common answer I get is “Of course, God created us”. Damn it dude then who created the God in the first place? I mean wait, which God are we talking about? Since the evolution of humans, there have been thousands of Gods created by humans. Krishna, Titans, Jesus, Buddha didn’t we create them? but why? Why did we create them? Where did this idea of God come from?</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Who created us? When I ask this question the very common answer I get is “Of course, God created us”. Damn it dude then who created the God in the first place? I mean wait, which God are we talking about? Since the evolution of humans, there have been thousands of Gods created by humans. Krishna, Titans, Jesus, Buddha didn’t we create them? but why? Why did we create them? Where did this idea of God come from? And then came the religions, castes, communities so many differences! I’m not answering these questions in this blog but I’m going to write about my opinion on these. (MY THOUGHTS)</p>
<p>What would you do if you were given a time machine? Would you travel to the past or the future? I’ve been asking this question for almost a decade now to everyone I acquaint with and the most common answer I get is to the future, the second most common is to go back a few years back and change something in their past. But if you ask me I’ll go back at least 5000 years back first to see how superly human was Lord Rama and then I’ll go and see how did they build those pyramids which are perfectly aligned to the constellation of stars which are more than a half a thousand light-years away! If they had done it with this much precision they couldn’t be the humans what we are now. This is just an example of what ancient humans did. We all must’ve read about so many more archeological mysteries that are not solved yet. City of Atlantis, Mayan civilization, and so many more! How did that all happen or what happened to all of them? So many theories and guesses but no proof. I don’t think it was God who did all these. Human evolution was at peak back then. Now I’m not sure if we are evolving or devolving. The researchers say the human body can’t devolve biologically but why do we all have a dormant photosensitive gland just behind our master gland inside our brain? Why did we stop using it? Why did we use it before? Again so many unanswered questions and many more theories.</p>
<p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/max/2795/1*dQ4ZCvKGCW3KofyGEm3mQg.jpeg" alt="Extent of Radio signals"></p>
<p>You see that tiny blue dot? That’s how much area we have covered so far with our Radio waves. This is an image of Milky way galaxy with an radius of about 53K Light-years with approximately 40K Crores of stars in which our Sun is one of them. This is just one galaxy in our Universe. There are about more than 100 billion galaxies estimated by our Hubble but there could be way more than that! And this is just in our Universe. Studies shows that we could be living in a multiverse where there are many universes like ours. Isn’t it amazing? To know that this cosmos came out of a singularity where there is no time and space. Sometimes I feel how tiny we are in this never ending cosmos. Who created that singularity? Who made it to expand? How did this all start? Many questions. Many theories.</p>
<p>The point is, in this huge cosmos being a minuscule creature with so many unanswered questions do we really need a God? What if I say each one of us is a God ourselves? What will it take for us to believe in ourselves?</p>
<p>கற்றது கைமண் அளவு, கல்லாதது உலகளவு — ஒளவையார்.</p>
<p>Known is a drop, unknown is an ocean — Avvaiyar.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
